Hello English learners.
各位英语学习者，大家好。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Kathryn.
我是Kathryn。
And today we've got a great show for you.
今天我们为大家准备了一期精彩的节目。
We're talking all about music.
我们要聊的全是关于音乐的话题。
It's a great topic.
这是个很棒的话题。
I think everyone loves music and well, there's so much type of music out there.
我觉得每个人都喜欢音乐，而且音乐的种类非常多。
So that's what we're going to be talking about today.
所以这就是我们今天要讨论的内容。
Exactly.
没错。
So there's a little bit for everyone here.
所以这里每个人都能找到适合自己的内容。
Even if you hate rock music, there might be something in it that you're going to be a
即使你讨厌摇滚乐，里面也可能有你会喜欢的
fan of.
东西。
Right.
对。
So before we get started on the dialogue, we have a couple of words that we want to
所以在开始对话之前，我们有几个词想先
preview.
预览一下。
So let's take a look at them now in Vocabulary Preview.
那我们现在就在词汇预览里看看它们吧。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So this word sounds a bit funny.
这个词听起来有点滑稽。
It looks like it should be pronounced differently.
它看起来发音应该不一样。
We say genre.
我们读作genre。
Genre.
Genre。
Or genre.
或者genre。
It kind of sounds French.
听起来有点像法语。
I think it comes from French.
我觉得它来自法语。
It's a GE word.
这是个GE词。
So genre.
所以是genre。
It's a soft, soft sound.
是轻柔、轻柔的音。
And what's a genre?
那什么是genre？
Well, a genre is like a category.
嗯，genre就像是一种类别。
So you could say genre of book or genre of music.
所以你可以说书的类型或音乐的类型。
Oh, movies also have genres, right?
哦，电影也有类型，对吧？
Yeah, they do.
是的，没错。
Like horror movie is a genre.
比如恐怖片就是一种类型。
Okay.
好的。
Or action or suspense, etc.
或者动作片、悬疑片等等。
So we're going to be looking at music genres on this occasion.
所以我们这次要探讨的是音乐类型。
And some of these genre names actually have abbreviations.
而且有些类型名称其实有缩写。
They're long words that we say in short forms.
它们是长词，我们用简短形式来说。
And this kind of abbreviation is called an acronym.
这种缩写形式叫做首字母缩略词。
All right.
好的。
So that's another word that we're looking at, acronym.
所以这是我们正在讨论的另一个词，首字母缩略词。
So an acronym is a short version of a long word.
首字母缩略词是一个长词的简短版本。
Yeah, usually it's just letters.
是的，通常只是几个字母。
Like USA is a very good acronym.
比如USA就是一个很好的首字母缩略词。
It means United States of America.
它代表美利坚合众国。
All right.
好的。
Cool.
酷。
So there are some acronyms as well in music.
音乐中也有一些首字母缩略词。
So that's what we're going to be looking at.
这就是我们要探讨的内容。
And many other things.
还有很多其他东西。
I guess like DNA is an acronym.
我猜DNA是一个首字母缩略词。
Yeah, DNA is an acronym.
是的，DNA是一个首字母缩略词。
UN is an acronym.
UN是一个首字母缩略词。
All right.
好的。
Great.
太棒了。
So we're going to be looking at different genres of music.
所以我们要看看不同的音乐流派。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
让我们第一次听对话。
We're going to listen to a game show where people have to name the song and the genre.
我们将听一个游戏节目，参赛者要猜出歌曲和流派。
Welcome back music lovers to I Love That Song, the game show where we test your musical knowledge
欢迎回来，音乐爱好者们，这里是《我爱那首歌》，一个测试你音乐知识的游戏节目，
to the extreme.
极限挑战。
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
Team A, guess this tune.
A队，猜猜这首曲子。
Carrying Your Love With Me by George Strait.
乔治·斯特雷特的《带着你的爱同行》。
The genre is country music.
流派是乡村音乐。
You're right.
答对了。
100 points to Team A. Now for our next cut.
A队得100分。现在听下一段。
Thong Song by Sisqó.
西斯克的《丁字裤之歌》。
I believe the genre is R&B.
我相信流派是R&B。
100 big points for Team B. For all of our viewers, the acronym R&B stands for rhythm
B队得100分。给所有观众解释一下，首字母缩略词R&B代表节奏
and blues.
和蓝调。
On that note, DJ, play our next song.
说到这里，DJ，播放下一首歌。
Superstar by The Carpenters.
卡朋特乐队的《超级巨星》。
And the genre?
流派是什么？
Adult Contemporary.
成人当代音乐。
That's right, 100 points.
没错，100分。
That sound means it's double or nothing.
这个声音意味着双倍或零分。
The songs are more difficult and the points are doubled.
歌曲更难，分数翻倍。
Let's hear our next song.
让我们听下一首歌。
Too Easy.
太简单了。
That song is Kingslayer by the Finnish power metal group Nightwish.
那首歌是芬兰力量金属乐队夜愿的《Kingslayer》。
You are correct.
你说对了。
Very impressive, Team A. And it seems we have a tie.
非常厉害，A队。看来我们打平了。
It's time now for the tiebreaker round.
现在是决胜局时间。
Each team will be played three songs and they must tell us the genre of each song in less
每队会听到三首歌，他们必须在五秒内说出每首歌的类型，
than five seconds.
少于五秒。
Team A, are you ready?
A队，准备好了吗？
Ready.
准备好了。
Let's hear it.
放出来听听。
Hip hop, classical and gothic metal.
嘻哈、古典和哥特金属。
You're right.
你们答对了。
Team B, the pressure is on.
B队，压力来了。
If you get all of them right, we will move on to sudden death.
如果你们全答对，我们就进入突然死亡环节。
If you miss one, you lose.
如果答错一个，你们就输了。
DJ, let's hear it.
DJ，放出来听听。
Rap, disco and...
说唱、迪斯科和……
Fun show, Marco.
有趣的节目，马可。
I kind of think I'd be good at this kind of game.
我有点觉得我擅长这种游戏。
I might win big.
我可能会大赢一把。
Well, there were a lot of different types of genres in there and a lot of different
嗯，那里有很多不同类型的音乐类型和很多不同的
music, I don't know, maybe not very popular.
音乐，我不知道，也许不太流行。
Like for example, country music.
比如，乡村音乐。
I don't know if many people outside of the United States actually know about this.
我不知道美国以外有多少人真正了解这个。
Well, there might be different kinds of country music, but you know, in America, one of the
嗯，可能有不同种类的乡村音乐，但你知道，在美国，最著名的
most famous country music musicians is Garth Brooks.
乡村音乐音乐家之一是加斯·布鲁克斯。
And even if I didn't like his music, I grew up hearing it everywhere.
即使我不喜欢他的音乐，我也是听着它长大的，到处都能听到。
But you don't like it?
但你不喜欢它？
Um, you know, it's one of those things that I like some kinds of country music, but it's
嗯，你知道，这是那种我喜欢某些乡村音乐的东西，但它是
a huge genre.
一个庞大的类型。
That means there's lots of different kinds of music within country.
这意味着乡村音乐里有很多不同种类的音乐。
All right.
好的。
So let's take a look at more of these genres and now in Language Takeaway.
那么让我们来看看更多这些类型，现在进入语言要点环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
So we talked about country music.
我们谈到了乡村音乐。
Now this is mostly in the United States, right?
这主要在美国，对吧？
In the South, especially because there's a long tradition of country music in the southern
在南方尤其如此，因为美国南方有悠久的乡村音乐传统。
United States.
所以它很有特色，有吉他……
So it's very characteristic to have guitars and...
A little bit of twang, maybe.
可能带点鼻音吧。
Twang?
鼻音？
What is twang?
什么是鼻音？
It's a way of saying a word.
就是一种发音方式。
So I could say, I'm from Texas, or I could say, I'm from Texas.
比如，我可以说“我来自德克萨斯”，或者“我来自德克萨斯”。
That's twang.
这就是鼻音。
So kind of like an accent, a southern accent.
所以有点像口音，南方口音。
Yeah.
对。
So Garth Brooks has a famous twang, I got friends in Laos.
所以加斯·布鲁克斯就有著名的鼻音，“我在老挝有朋友”。
You know, that's a very famous song of his where he's twangy.
你知道，那是他很有名的一首歌，唱起来带鼻音。
Very southern.
非常南方。
Yeah.
对。
All right.
好吧。
So we have country music and then we saw another genre, which is R&B.
所以我们有乡村音乐，然后我们看到了另一种类型，就是R&B。
Okay.
好的。
This is a little bit more up my alley.
这个更对我的胃口。
That means this is more of an interest of mine.
意思是这更符合我的兴趣。
And R&B is an acronym for?
那R&B是哪个词的缩写？
Rhythm and blues.
节奏布鲁斯。
All right.
好吧。
So the R&B that we know now, what would be some examples of those artists?
那我们现在知道的R&B，有哪些艺人的例子？
Well, a really famous artist is John Legend, who's been touring the world with his new
嗯，一个很有名的艺人是约翰·传奇，他带着新专辑在世界巡演，
album and that kind of music is R&B.
那种音乐就是R&B。
So we're talking about a kind of music that mixes jazz traditions with rhythm.
所以我们说的是融合了爵士传统和节奏的音乐。
So that means drums and bass.
也就是鼓和贝斯。
Okay.
好的。
That's rhythm.
那就是节奏。
So you have rhythm and blues, like the name says.
所以就像名字说的，有节奏和布鲁斯。
R&B, very popular nowadays.
R&B，现在非常流行。
And then we moved on to something heavier, something more like rock style, which is metal.
然后我们转向更重一点的，更像摇滚风格的音乐，那就是金属。
Metal.
金属。
Okay.
好的。
I'm not really sure why they call it metal, but metal is a very, very popular kind of
我不太确定为什么叫它金属，但金属是一种非常非常流行的
music.
音乐。
So it divides into different categories, right?
所以它分成不同的类别，对吧？
In this song, we saw that it was power metal.
在这首歌里，我们看到它是力量金属。
Yeah.
对。
But you also have like heavy metal.
但还有像重金属这样的。
Well, because metal is such a broad category, it's a big category.
嗯，因为金属是一个很宽泛的类别，是个大类别。
It's hard to say what certain groups are unless you're really a fan and you follow, but there
除非你是真正的乐迷并且一直关注，否则很难说清某些金属流派具体是什么，但
are many different kinds of metal out there.
金属乐其实有很多不同的种类。
And so if you're interested, I would check it out on Wikipedia.
所以如果你感兴趣，我建议你去维基百科上查查。
Yeah.
是啊。
Or let us know if you know what's the difference between power metal and gothic metal and electronic
或者告诉我们，如果你知道力量金属、哥特金属和电子金属之间的区别，
metal.
金属。
So there are so many different types now.
所以现在有这么多不同的类型。
But moving on to our next genre, we also saw something that everyone probably knows nowadays
但接下来我们聊聊下一个音乐类型，我们也都看到了一种现在大家可能都知道的，
and that's hip hop.
那就是嘻哈。
Yeah.
是啊。
Hip hop is a great, great and very interesting kind of music.
嘻哈是一种非常棒、非常有趣且很有意思的音乐。
It grew out of a lot of people who are listening to jazz in the late 80s, especially in New
它源于很多在80年代末听爵士乐的人，尤其是在纽约，
York, I think, Brooklyn.
我想是布鲁克林。
And it's kind of interesting in the sense that you take these old records, these old
而且有趣的是，你会拿这些老唱片、这些老
vinyls, and you slow everything down.
黑胶唱片，然后把所有东西都放慢。
Right.
对。
So you change the speed.
所以你改变了速度。
So a normal song goes from dum, dum, dum, dum to dum, dum, dum, dum.
所以一首正常的歌从“咚、咚、咚、咚”变成了“咚、咚、咚、咚”。
And then you had like some bass in there.
然后里面再加点低音。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
And some lyrics and you have yourself something like hip hop.
再加上一些歌词，你就有了类似嘻哈的东西。
So a very famous hip hop artist nowadays would be 50 Cent.
现在一个非常著名的嘻哈艺人就是50 Cent。
Yeah.
是啊。
Or for example, also Nelly, right?
或者比如，还有Nelly，对吧？
Another famous hip hop artist.
另一个著名的嘻哈艺人。
Yeah.
是啊。
So we have hip hop and well, it's kind of similar.
所以我们有嘻哈，嗯，它有点类似。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Very similar to rap almost.
几乎和说唱非常相似。
Yeah.
是啊。
But it's different in that the way the process for making this kind of music is quite different.
但不同之处在于，制作这种音乐的过程相当不一样。
Yeah.
是啊。
Rap tends to be very lyric heavy, whereas hip hop is very beat heavy, I think.
说唱往往非常注重歌词，而嘻哈则非常注重节奏，我觉得。
Right.
对。
So interesting.
真有意思。
Now we've seen a lot of these different genres, but of course, there's so many more that we
我们已经看到了很多不同的音乐类型，但当然，还有更多我们
can't really look at all of them in one single podcast.
不可能在一个播客里全部讲完。
That's what our website's for.
这就是我们网站的作用。
You can put your favorite music genres up on our website and practice your English.
你可以把你最喜欢的音乐类型放到我们的网站上，并练习你的英语。
Exactly.
没错。
So, well, why don't we listen to this dialogue for the second time?
那么，我们为什么不第二次听这段对话呢？
Let's slow it down just a little bit, and then we'll come back and look at some more
让我们稍微放慢速度，然后回来再看一些
phrases.
短语。
Welcome back, music lovers, to I Love That Song, the game show where we test your musical
欢迎回来，音乐爱好者们，来到《我爱那首歌》，这个游戏节目将测试你的音乐
knowledge to the extreme.
知识到极致。
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
Team A, guess this tune.
A队，猜猜这首曲子。
Carrying Your Love With Me by George Strait.
《Carrying Your Love With Me》，乔治·斯特雷特演唱。
The genre is country music.
类型是乡村音乐。
You're right.
你说对了。
100 points to Team A. Now for our next cut.
A队得100分。现在进入下一首曲目。
Song Song by Sisqó.
《Song Song》，西斯克演唱。
I believe the genre is R&B.
我相信类型是R&B。
100 big points for Team B.
B队得100分。
For all of our viewers, the acronym R&B stands for rhythm and blues.
对于所有观众来说，缩写R&B代表节奏布鲁斯。
On that note, DJ, play our next song.
说到这里，DJ，播放我们的下一首歌。
Superstar by The Carpenters.
《Superstar》，卡朋特乐队演唱。
And the genre?
那类型呢？
Adult Contemporary.
成人当代。
That's right.
没错。
100 points.
100分。
Uh-oh.
哦哦。
That sound means it's double or nothing.
那个声音意味着这是双倍或零分。
The songs are more difficult and the points are doubled.
歌曲更难了，分数也翻倍了。
Let's hear our next song.
让我们听听下一首歌。
Too easy.
太简单了。
That song is Kingslayer by the Finnish power metal group Nightwish.
那首歌是《Kingslayer》，由芬兰力量金属乐队夜愿演唱。
You are correct.
你说对了。
Very impressive, Team A. And it seems we have a tie.
非常令人印象深刻，A队。看来我们打平了。
It's time now for the tiebreaker round.
现在是决胜局的时候了。
Each team will be played three songs, and they must tell us the genre of each song in
每队将听到三首歌，他们必须在
less than five seconds.
五秒内告诉我们每首歌的类型。
Team A, are you ready?
A队，准备好了吗？
Ready.
准备好了。
Let's hear it.
放出来听听。
Hip-hop, classical, and gothic metal.
嘻哈、古典和哥特金属。
You're right.
你说对了。
Team B, the pressure is on.
B队，压力来了。
If you get all of them right, we will move on to sudden death.
如果你们全部答对，我们将进入突然死亡环节。
If you miss one, you lose.
如果答错一个，你们就输了。
DJ, let's hear it.
DJ，放出来听听。
Rap, disco, and...
说唱、迪斯科和……
So, it isn't a true EnglishPod lesson if we don't give you a couple of phrases and words
所以，如果我们不给你一些短语和词汇
to make you sound more fluent, so that's the purpose of this next portion of our show.
让你听起来更流利，那就不是真正的EnglishPod课程了，这就是我们节目下一部分的目的。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, so the phrases that we're going to look at now on Fluency Builder are the ones that
好的，所以我们现在要在流利度构建器中看的短语是那些
we saw in the dialogue, but we can use, of course, outside of music or outside of a game
我们在对话中看到的，但当然，我们可以在音乐或游戏节目之外使用。
show.
And there was an interesting one that he mentioned when he said, double or nothing.
他提到一个有趣的短语，当他说“双倍或零分”时。
Hmm, double or nothing.
嗯，双倍或零分。
It's double or nothing.
这是双倍或零分。
Well, this is an interesting phrase because it, I think, comes from gambling and betting.
嗯，这是一个有趣的短语，因为我认为它来自赌博和打赌。
Yeah, so it's a way for us to say, well, you could double your money, but if you have
是的，所以这是一种说法，你可以双倍赢钱，但如果你
a bad answer, if you lose this round, you don't get anything.
回答错误，如果你输掉这一轮，你什么都得不到。
So I guess, yeah, you do see a lot of people say, maybe they're betting or they're playing
所以我想，是的，你确实看到很多人说，也许他们在打赌或玩
a game, that person loses and says, okay, let's go double or nothing.
游戏，那个人输了然后说，好吧，让我们来个双倍或零分。
So give me one more shot to win back my money.
所以再给我一次机会赢回我的钱。
Right.
对。
So if I say, okay, Marco, you need to tell me the capital of Brazil, you have $50.
所以如果我说，好的，Marco，你需要告诉我巴西的首都，你有50美元。
If you get the answer right, you get $100.
如果你答对了，你得到100美元。
But if you get the answer wrong, you get zero.
但如果你答错了，你得到零。
Right.
对。
That's double or nothing.
那就是双倍或零分。
All right, interesting phrase.
好的，有趣的短语。
What else do we have?
我们还有什么？
We've got a great one here called tiebreaker.
我们有一个很棒的短语叫“决胜局”。
So a tiebreaker.
所以是决胜局。
Yeah, a tiebreaker, it's a thing.
是的，决胜局，这是一个东西。
And sometimes in games, some people have the same score.
有时在游戏中，有些人有相同的分数。
They have the same amount of points.
他们有相同的分数。
So they're tied.
所以他们打平了。
They're tied.
他们打平了。
A tie means you have the same number.
平局意味着你们有相同的数字。
And if you want to win, you need one winner.
如果你想赢，你需要一个赢家。
You have to have a tiebreaker to decide.
你必须有一个决胜局来决定。
So it could be a question or like we saw here, a tiebreaker round.
所以可能是一个问题，或者像我们这里看到的，一个决胜局回合。
Yeah.
是的。
So to decide on a winner.
所以来决定一个赢家。
And this is all or nothing because if you get the answer right, you win.
这是全有或全无，因为如果你答对了，你就赢了。
If you don't, you lose.
如果你答错了，你就输了。
It doesn't matter if you were tied before.
之前是否打平并不重要。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
A tiebreaker.
一个决胜局。
And we have one more phrase and this one is really interesting.
我们还有一个短语，这个真的很有趣。
The pressure is on.
压力来了。
So if I say the pressure is on.
所以如果我说压力来了。
It almost sounds painful.
听起来几乎很痛苦。
Yeah, it does.
是的，确实。
Well, is it, does it mean that I am being pressured or what is this?
嗯，这是不是意味着我正受到压力，还是什么？
Well, it's a good question.
嗯，这是个好问题。
The important thing to look at here is the word on because pressure has this kind of
这里要注意的重点是“on”这个词，因为压力有这种
companion word to put pressure on something or to put pressure on someone.
伴随词，比如“给某物施加压力”或“给某人施加压力”。
And so it's the way we say it in English and it means that you're going to really take
所以这是我们用英语表达的方式，意思是你要从此刻起
things seriously from this point on.
认真对待事情。
Okay.
好的。
Right.
对。
So for example, the Chicago Bulls were at the peak, the height of their fame and they
所以例如，芝加哥公牛队处于巅峰，他们名声鼎盛，
were just a wonderful team.
他们是一支非常棒的球队。
And oftentimes you'd hear the announcers say, there's five seconds left on the clock.
而且你经常听到解说员说，比赛还剩五秒。
The pressure is on Michael Jordan to win the game.
压力落在了迈克尔·乔丹身上，他要赢得比赛。
All right.
好的。
So the opportunity for the team to win all depended on Michael Jordan.
所以球队获胜的机会完全取决于迈克尔·乔丹。
Right.
对。
So the pressure, all of this stuff is on him, his shoulders.
所以压力，所有这些都压在他身上，他的肩膀上。
So he has to score the point to win the game.
所以他必须得分才能赢得比赛。
Okay.
好的。
This is a very interesting phrase.
这是一个非常有趣的短语。
Why don't we take a look at some other examples of how we could use the pressure is on.
我们为什么不看看其他一些如何使用“压力来了”的例子呢。
Example one.
例子一。
Carl is really stressed out lately.
卡尔最近压力很大。
The pressure of the entire project is on him since his promotion.
自从他升职以来，整个项目的压力都落在他身上。
Example two.
例子二。
The pressure is on the president to guide his country out of the recession.
总统面临着引导国家走出衰退的压力。
Example three.
例子三。
The pressure is on our entire team to successfully come up with a new product for the Asian market
我们整个团队面临着在一个月内成功为亚洲市场推出新产品的压力。
within a month.
All right.
好的。
Great examples.
很好的例子。
Great phrases.
很棒的短语。
I think it's pretty clear now, right?
我想现在很清楚了，对吧？
It is.
是的。
And to make sure that we understood the whole dialogue, I think we should take another listen
为了确保我们理解了整个对话，我认为我们应该以正常速度再听一遍。
to it at a normal speed.
And when we come back, we'll be talking a little bit more about one of my favorite topics,
当我们回来时，我们将多聊一些我最喜欢的话题之一，
music.
音乐。
Welcome back music lovers to I Love That Song, the game show where we test your musical knowledge
欢迎回来，音乐爱好者们，来到《我爱那首歌》，这个游戏节目将测试你的音乐知识到极致。
to the extreme.
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
Team A, guess this tune.
A队，猜猜这首曲子。
Carrying your love with me by George Strait.
《Carrying Your Love With Me》，乔治·斯特雷特演唱。
The genre is country music.
类型是乡村音乐。
You're right.
你说对了。
100 points to Team A. Now for our next cut.
A队得100分。现在进入下一首曲目。
Song sung by Cisco.
《Song Song》，西斯克演唱。
I believe the genre is R&B.
我相信类型是R&B。
100 big points for Team B. For all of our viewers, the acronym R&B stands for rhythm
B队得100分。对于所有观众来说，缩写R&B代表节奏
and blues.
布鲁斯。
On that note, DJ, play our next song.
说到这里，DJ，播放我们的下一首歌。
Superstar by the Carpenters.
《Superstar》，卡朋特乐队演唱。
And the genre?
那类型呢？
Adult contemporary.
成人当代。
That's right, 100 points.
没错，100分。
Uh-oh, that sound means it's double or nothing.
哦哦，那个声音意味着这是双倍或零分。
The songs are more difficult and the points are doubled.
歌曲更难了，分数也翻倍了。
Let's hear our next song.
让我们听听下一首歌。
Too easy.
太简单了。
That song is Kingslayer by the Finnish power metal group Nightwish.
那首歌是《Kingslayer》，由芬兰力量金属乐队夜愿演唱。
You are correct.
你说对了。
Very impressive, Team A. And it seems we have a tie.
非常令人印象深刻，A队。看来我们打平了。
It's time now for the tiebreaker round.
现在是决胜局的时候了。
Each team will be played three songs and they must tell us the genre of each song in less
每队将听到三首歌，他们必须在五秒内告诉我们每首歌的类型。
than five seconds.
Team A, are you ready?
A队，准备好了吗？
Ready.
准备好了。
Let's hear it.
放出来听听。
Hip hop, classical and gothic metal.
嘻哈、古典和哥特金属。
You're right.
你说对了。
Team B, the pressure is on.
B队，压力来了。
If you get all of them right, we will move on to sudden death.
如果你们全部答对，我们将进入突然死亡环节。
If you miss one, you lose.
如果答错一个，你们就输了。
DJ, let's hear it.
DJ，放出来听听。
Rap, disco and...
说唱、迪斯科和……
All right, so we have music, different music genres.
好的，所以我们有音乐，不同的音乐类型。
Which one are you mostly into?
你最喜欢哪一种？
That's a hard question.
这是个很难的问题。
I have very different interests.
我有非常不同的兴趣。
I like classical music.
我喜欢古典音乐。
I also like jazz, but I also like rock and I also like R&B.
我也喜欢爵士乐，但我也喜欢摇滚和R&B。
So it really depends.
所以真的要看情况。
I guess it depends on your mood.
我想这取决于你的心情。
Absolutely.
绝对。
Now, they say that music does really influence people's moods.
现在，他们说音乐确实会影响人们的情绪。
They did a study, some doctors in America did a study to see if heart patients, people
他们做了一项研究，美国的一些医生做了一项研究，看看心脏病患者，有心脏问题的人，
who have heart problems, could be positively affected by music.
是否能被音乐积极影响。
And the results said that yes, it can be helpful.
结果说是的，它可能是有帮助的。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
So maybe it helps them relax or...
所以也许它帮助他们放松或……
Yeah, it says if you're listening to the radio and a song that you like comes on the radio,
是的，它说如果你在听收音机，一首你喜欢的歌在收音机里播放，
you hear the song, your heart pumps more oxygen to your brain.
你听到这首歌，你的心脏会向大脑输送更多氧气。
So it means it actually makes you happier.
所以这意味着它实际上让你更快乐。
Wow.
哇。
What about when they play music for unborn babies?
那当他们为未出生的婴儿播放音乐时呢？
Like they'll put little headphones on a mother's belly and they'll play like classical music
就像他们会把一个小耳机放在母亲的肚子上，然后播放古典音乐，
because supposedly it'll make the baby smarter.
因为据说这会让宝宝更聪明。
Like baby Mozart or something.
就像小莫扎特之类的。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
What do you think about that?
你怎么看？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think talking to kids and giving them books when they're little probably helps a little
我认为在孩子小的时候和他们说话、给他们书可能更有帮助，
bit more, but I'm not a doctor so that I can't say.
但我不是医生，所以我不能这么说。
Well, many people do argue now that they don't make music like they used to.
嗯，现在很多人争论说，他们不再像以前那样制作音乐了。
I guess they say that music that was made before, the lyrics were more profound, they
我想他们说以前制作的音乐，歌词更深刻，他们是真正的音乐家，
were real musicians, they were composers and they wrote lyrics.
他们是作曲家和作词人。
But now you just get a lot of temporary music that doesn't really transcend into the future.
但现在你只得到很多临时音乐，并不能真正流传到未来。
What do you think?
你怎么看？
I totally disagree.
我完全不同意。
I think the last 10 years have seen a really amazing growth in the music industry because
我认为过去十年音乐产业经历了惊人的增长，因为
more people are communicating.
越来越多的人在交流。
The internet allows us to hear all sorts of things from all over the world and so we have
互联网让我们能听到来自世界各地的各种声音，所以我们有了
great musicians who can listen to music from Mali and they can listen to music from India
伟大的音乐家，他们可以听来自马里的音乐，也可以听来自印度的音乐
and they have all these different influences that were not there before.
他们拥有了以前没有的各种不同影响。
And so I think it's the opposite.
所以我认为情况恰恰相反。
I think a lot of new pathways in music have opened up because of the technology evolution.
我认为，由于技术进化，音乐中许多新的路径已经打开。
Wow, interesting.
哇，有意思。
Well, what do you guys think?
嗯，你们觉得呢？
Listeners, come to our website EnglishPod.com, leave your questions and comments and tell
听众们，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，留下你们的问题和评论，并告诉我们
us what you think.
你们的想法。
Do you think maybe music has become better in the last decade or do you think maybe it's
你们觉得过去十年音乐变得更好，还是可能
not so good?
没那么好？
Well, you do have bad artists, right?
嗯，确实有糟糕的艺术家，对吧？
You always have bad artists.
糟糕的艺术家总是存在的。
The bad ones, they fade into history.
那些糟糕的，会逐渐被历史遗忘。
You never hear from them again.
你再也不会听到他们的消息。
So come and let us know and also if you have any questions or doubts, you can leave them
所以来吧，让我们知道，如果你们有任何问题或疑惑，也可以
on the site as well.
在网站上留言。
Yeah, we're happy to answer any questions you've got.
是的，我们很乐意回答你们的任何问题。
So let us know what you're thinking.
所以告诉我们你们的想法。
All right, we'll see you guys there and until next time.
好了，我们会在那里见你们，下次再见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。